Guide to the Harrison Flint Lewis papers, 1913-1974.
Flint, Harrison papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Harrison Flint Lewis papers, 1913-1974.
3696
Lewis, Harrison Flint,
.8 cubic ft.
Research material, printed material, publications
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Papers include speeches; published and unpublished articles; 92 notebooks of bird sightings, 1913-1974; annotated bird photographs, 1933, 1936, and 1940; a list of Lewis' publications; and other materials concerning ornithology.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Harrison Flint Lewis (Cornell University Ph.D. 1929), an ornithologist and writer, was in charge of the administration of migratory bird protection in Ontario and Quebec, 1920-1944; superintendent for Wildlife Protection for Canada, 1944-1947; chief, Canadian Wildlife Service, 1947-1952; and editor, "The Canadian Field-Naturalist," 1922-1925.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Papers include speeches; published and unpublished articles; 92 notebooks of bird sightings, 1913-1974; annotated bird photographs, 1933, 1936, and 1940; a list of Lewis' publications; and other materials concerning ornithology.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Lewis, Harrison Flint, 1893-1974.
Subjects:
Ornithology.; Birds -- Migration; Ornithologists.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Logs (Records)
INFORMATION FOR USERS
NOTES
Correspondence from Lewis is included in the Arthur A. Allen Papers, #21-18-1255.
CONTAINER LIST
- Bird Log Books, 1913-1974 (Box 1)
  Logbooks from May 23, 1937-August 21, 1939 and May 25, 1952-June 23, 1959 are in Box 2. Usually the summer sightings fill a notebook and the rest of the academic year's sightings fill another notebook.
- Bird Log Books, 1937-1939 (Box 2)
- Bird Log Books, 1952-1959 (Box 2)
- Bibliography: "Publications of Harrison Flint Lewis" (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Articles and reprints by Harrison Flint Lewis, 1921-1954 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Manuscripts by Harrison Flint Lewis, 1931-1968 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Bird Observation and Migration Logs, 1918-1923 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  For the United States Department of Agriculture, Form B1-155
- Bird Observation Log (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Facimiles of United States Department of Agriculture, Form B1-155, dates uncertain because it has been coded without the key.
- Bird Observation Log, 1908-1920 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Handwritten and hand-bound record of sightings by bird species over time. Information taken from notebooks in Box 1 and written out at a later time.
- Travel photographs - mainly Canada., 1933-1940 (and undated) (Box 2, Folder 7)